Guide to the Vassar College Campus Life and Diversity Office Records, 1988-2022
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Campus Life and Diversity Office Records
1988-2022
Vassar College. Campus Life and Diversity Office
7 cubic feet (10 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Minutes, reports, correspondence and other material created by the Office of Student Life and Diversity. Also included are audiovisual materials, including VHS and compact disc recordings of baccalaureate ceremonies; photographs; event flyers and posters; and realia including mugs, t-shirts, and pens.
Administrative History
The history of the Campus Life and Diversity Office is closely tied to the Vassar career of Edward Pittman. Pittman, a member of Vassar's Class of 1982, began working for the college in 1990 in the newly-created Office of Multicultural Affairs, a division of the Dean of Student Life.
Sources: Vassar College Miscellany News and Vassar College Biographical Files (Serge Paul Emile)
Chronology
1974 September President Alan Simpson appointed Serge Paul-Emile as first Director of Educational Services and Student Relations
1983 Special Services Program, Academic Resource Center
1983 Advisor to Minority and Special Students = Sheila Thomas
Fall 1990 Creation of the Office of Multicultural Affairs
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains minutes, reports, correspondence and other material created by the Office of Student Life and Diversity. Also included are audiovisual materials, including VHS and compact disc recordings of baccalaureate ceremonies; photographs; event flyers and posters; and realia including mugs, t-shirts, pens, and other give-aways from All College Day, the First Year Experience, and other events.
Access
The material in Box 8 is restricted. Otherwise, the collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Vassar College Jeh Vincent Johnson ALANA Cultural Center Records
Vassar College LGBTQ Center (Lesbian, Bisexual, Transgender and Queer Center) Records
Vassar College Women's Center Records
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Administration; Vassar College--Students
Document Types:
Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Correspondence; Financial records; Photographs; Posters; Printed ephemera; Realia; Reports; Videocassettes
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, April 2019. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, January 2023.
Acquisition Information
Transferred in three accessions from the Office of Campus Life and Diversity: A2016-006, A2019-014, and A2021-026.
Series List
- Series I. Office files, 1988-2018
- Series II. Audiovisual Material, 1993-2014
- Series III. Ephemera, 1990-2022
- Series IV. Realia, circa 2004-2018
Container List
- Series I. Office Files
  - Annual Reports — Advisor to Minority Students, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports — Office of Multicultural Affairs, 1990-1992 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports — Dean of Student Life / Intercultural Center, 1992-1998; (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports — ALANA Student Cultural Center, 2002-2004 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports — ALANA and LGBTQ Center, 2011-2012 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports — Campus Life Office, 2002-2008 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous reports and Summaries (Box 3)
  - Multicultural concerns pre-1990 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 3)
  - ALANA opening and history, (9 folders) (Box 3)
  - Admissions and recruitment, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - AKBAR (Box 3)
  - All College Day, 2002-2008; (12 folders) (Box 3)
  - AAAVC (Box 3)
  - Angela Davis / Community (Box 3)
  - Athletics, homophobia, heterosexism, 2007 August (Box 3)
  - Baccalaureate Service programs, 1995-2018 (Box 3)
  - Black/Jewish Community Dialogue, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Black Solidarity Conference, Yale University, 1998; (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Campus Life handouts (Box 3)
  - Campus Life Office (Box 3)
  - Campus Life Resources Group — History and Background, 2006-2011; (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Campus Life Resources Group — History and Background, 2012 (Box 4)
  - Campus Life Resources Group, 2001-2009; (8 folders) (Box 4)
  - Campus Life Response Team, 2007-2008; (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Campus Life staff meeting, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Campus Life — miscellaneous, circa 2000-2018 (Box 4)
  - Committee on Diversity and Difference, 2001-2002; (9 folders) (Box 4)
  - Community Day, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Community Meeting, 2003 January 30 (Box 4)
  - Consortium on High Achievement and Success, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Council of Black Seniors, 2007-2012; (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - Cross Cultural Training, 1990 October 18 (Box 4)
  - Diversity reports (Box 5)
  - Diversity — miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Elected student leaders, 2003-2007 (Box 5)
  - LGBTQ (Box 5)
  - Minority retention and recruitment, (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - Mixing it up: Intergroup dialogue program, 2005 (Box 5)
  - NCBI Workshop, 2015; (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - Poughkeepsie High School partnership, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Race Relations Task Force, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Racial/Ethnic Relations Conference, San Antonio, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Student Groups (Box 5)
  - Students for Justice in Palestine, 2014 (Box 5)
  - Moderate, Independent and Conservative Alliance (MICA), 2005-2006; (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - Vassar First Year Experience, (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - Westboro response (Box 5)
  - Minority group lists, (23 folders) (Box 5)
  - International students lists, (9 folders) (Box 5)
  - Ford Grant, 1995-1997; (5 folders) (Box 6)
  - Unprocessed [Restricted], 1990-2005 (Box 8)
- Series II. Audiovisual Material
  - Compact Discs
    - Vassar College Baccalaureate, 2008 May 24 (Box 6)
    - Vassar College Baccalaureate, 2009 May (Box 6)
    - Vassar College Baccalaureate, 2011 May (Box 6)
    - Vassar College Baccalaureate, 2012 May (Box 6)
    - Vassar College Baccalaureate, 2013 May (Box 6)
    - Vassar College Baccalaureate, 2014 May; (2 discs) (Box 6)
  - Photographs
    - All College Day, 2003 February 19 (Box 6)
    - All College Day - Playback Theatre, 2003 February 19 (Box 6)
    - All College Day - Talent Event, 2003 February 19 (Box 6)
    - All College Day, 2004 (Box 6)
    - Conversation Dinners, 2003 (Box 6)
  - VHS Tapes
    - "All College Day 2005 - Arlington/Vassar," (Box 6)
    - "All College Day 2005 - Blegen/Baseball Dialogue," (Box 6)
    - "Baccalaureate Ceremony,", 2000 May 20; (5 tapes) (Box 6)
    - "Baccalaureate Ceremony - Council of Black Seniors,", 2003 May 24 (Box 6)
    - "Baccalaureate Ceremony, Vassar College - Speaker Reverend James Forbes,", 1999 May 22; (2 tapes) (Box 6)
    - "Baccalaureate Service,", 1997 (Box 6)
    - "Baccalaureate Service,", 1998 May 23; (2 tapes) (Box 6)
    - "'Out of the Past' - Ed Pittman, Bethel Church,", undated (Box 6)
    - "Triple A [Vassar College] - Villard Room (Part 2),", 1993 November 6 (Box 6)
    - "Vegas Documentary on Diversity at Vassar College ALANA Center,", undated (Box 6)
- Series III. Ephemera
  - Flyers and leaflets, circa 2007-2020 (Box 6)
  - Flyers and leaflets — All College Day, 2001-2014 (Box 6)
  - Flyers and leaflets — First Year (Box 6)
  - Flyers and leaflets — LGBTQ Center (Box 6)
  - Flyers and leaflets — Women's Center (Box 6)
  - Flyers and leaflets — ALANA Center (Box 6)
  - Flyers and leaflets — Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Posters, 1990, 2005-2022; (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - Posters — ALANA Center, 2005-2015; (1 folder) (Box 7)
  - Posters — All-College Day, 2002-2015; (1 folder) (Box 7)
  - Posters — All-College Day, 2006-2011 (Box 9 (Oversize Roll Box))
  - Posters — First Year, 2007-2015; (1 folder) (Box 7)
  - Posters — LGBTQ Center, 2008-2014, undated; (1 folder) (Box 7)
  - Posters — Women's Center, 2010, undated; (1 folder) (Box 7)
  - Privilege Campaign — posters, 2015-2016 (Box 7)
  - Privilege Campaign, Year III — photographic posters, 2016 (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Privilege Campaign, Year III — student statements, 2016; (2 folders) (Box 6)
- Series IV. Realia
  - Realia, circa 2004-2018; (Mugs, t-shirts, pens, and more) (Boxes 1-2)